Hi friends, in this video we will talk about a
company called ICICI LBAD.  What does ICICI LBA
do?  So basically ICICI LBA is
inu general insurance.  So
if we understand insurance, we can basically
divide it into two parts.  A life
insurance in which let's suppose somebody gets
the insurance and if it dies then
whatever coverage is there against him, he gets that
amount.  Apart from this, in your
general insurance, basically there is
own damage of your car, that is,
if the car meets with an accident somewhere, then the
claim is received against the damage caused to it
or third party, that is, let's suppose if
someone collides with the car and has some
accident, gets injured or dies, then
payment is made for that.  There is insurance
around the health that you take health insurance
and then if you have to be hospitalized then the
premium that you get for that is for
health.  There is marine
insurance which is
insurance related to travel related to sea.  So
basically ICICI Lo Lar does general insurance,
it does not do life insurance.  So this is
it.  Now, if we
talk about their overall segment, then their market share in motor segment,
which includes your on-damage pay and
third party,
is around 10.7% and if we talk about market share in retail health or
group health, then
till last time their market share in retail was 3.3%, which has
now become 4.1%.  Meaning,
their growth in the retail health insurance segment has been
more than 50% in the full year as well as in Q4.
And the basic reason for this is that the company has
said that considering the GST has been removed on
health insurance plans and everything.
So now they are able to capture more customers, there are
new customers coming in for the
insurance.  So that's one reason.  Second
is the group, their market share in health insurance is
8.7%,
apart from this, basically if I say,
their motor segment contributes 40% of the business
and health insurance
contributes 32%.  So roughly around 72% of the
business goes to these two
segments.  Then in the remaining 28% of yours,
your marine also came, others
also came, crop also came, this also came.
But the major focus is here.
What is the USP of Now Company?  The USP of this company is that one is
obviously its wide distribution
network and it also has its own ICICI banking
branches.  It is also through other banks and
they also have their own agents.  Then they go
digital and all that perspective.  So the
distribution channel is definitely one of theirs,
the USB.  This is their second major USP.
Through their automated and digitized system which is their platform, they generate leads
, do renewals and do claim
settlement.  So That Remains One of
Their USB.  So these two things the company has
emphasized during the call are the reasons for their growth.
Third is that it is
always very important in the insurance business that
you do not
sell all the insurance policies at once.  Where
you feel the risk is high, you should
not do the insurance.  In fact,
if you have ever read the letter of Warren Buffett, then
he has an insurance company in which there is a guy named
Ajay Jain,
his employee who keeps on saying that Ajay Jain knows better
when to take the business and when to move on, so that is how
it is very relevant in this business.
As far as future growth levers are concerned,
one is obviously the company acknowledges
that there is too much competition but then again they
said that the combined ratio of
some players is 128%.  Meaning, what does a low combined
ratio mean, that you
earned a premium of ₹100 and your
ultimately settled claim plus
your expenses came to ₹128, then it means that the
company will close down sooner or later from that race.
So from that perspective the
company emphasized that while there
is competitiveness but their combined ratios are
so high, expenses are so high, then
ultimately sooner than later the competition will reduce.
Secondly, the company said that there are some
regulatory changes expected in which the
government will make the rules more stringent.
So where in there it is said that since they
already follow the rules, then if the
rules become applicable to other players who do not follow the
rules
or become applicable to the entire industry, then they will have an advantage,
meaning they will
benefit from it.  As far as the numbers are concerned, if we
look at the numbers, if we
talk about premium, the growth of premium
is 18.2% in Q4 and 7% in FY26 full year
and if we talk about profitability, the growth of PAT is
7.3% in Q4 and 10.5 in full year.
So, from that perspective, if we
look at it, and the company is trading at a PE of
33.8%, then it means it is like three times of the
bag. They already have a
big market share as in, which means if I talk about
your motor sector, it is
10.7, then it means there are too many
players, they can't go on board at the same
time. If we talk about their risk
management, then as I said, their
combined end ratio is 1134% year-end PE, which essentially
means they are
very conservative and there is
no chance of loss and the return and RO is also 17.8%,
so from that perspective, the numbers are good, but from a
valuation perspective, this seems to be expensive. I mean, there is
no point buying
a stock which is in the insurance sector,
where the risk is inherently high.
Secondly, its growth rate is around 10-12% and the
valuation is at Rs 33.  So not a very great
opportunity to see but anyway a good idea
to track the base and
observe thank you?